## **Andrew A Hamlin**

aahamlin@gmail.com (860) 810 - 6538 https://aahamlin.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewahamlin

### **SUMMARY**

With a background in full stack application and distributed Enterprise system development including Waterfall, XP, Agile, Lean environments from tech startups to a Fortune 100 company, I have worked in all stages of the SDLC, managed sustained engineering teams and supported partner relationships.

I am a champion for software craftsmanship and servant leadership. And strive to create or enhance team cultures of humility, respect, integrity and accountability.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Sr Software Development Manager Gerber Technology, LLC 2018 - present

Coach individuals and teams in Agile-Lean improvements. Decreased lead time (-77%), cycle time (-81.5%) and rejection rate (-5.3%) over last 3 product releases. Collaborate with Product, QA and Dev teams on planning and delivery of 2D/3D CAD roadmap and tp strategically address technical debt. Champion adoption of a CI/CD workflow using Git, AWS CodeCommit, Jenkins including unit and integration test automation. Leading technical integration of a digital avatar platform. Manage 7 developers and 10 offshore.

# Software Development Manager Sailpoint Technologies 2016 - 2018

Worked with senior leadership to improve all design, build and test procedures; increasing predictability and code quality. Scrum master of 2 teams; totaling 16 dev & test engineers. Established business process and added 4 languages from a new vendor. Led teams developing Java, SQL, Angular.js, REST API, SCIM API, OAuth 2.0, Multi-Factor Authentication with Duo and RSA, credential cycling with CyberArk and BeyondTrust, and Accessibility compliance with Section 508 and WCAG 2.

# Software Development Manager/Team Lead Caradigm USA, LLC 2013 - 2016

Delivered 2 products to market. Led 6-person team developing an SDK for RFID Reader integration with Linux VDIs from Dell Wyse, HP SmartZero and Teradici using Java, C, and Python and extended build system support for ARM & Intel processors. Led 10-person team developing an identify governance solution including Microsoft

#### Andrew A Hamlin

SQL w/ SSIS, MVC5, HTML/CSS, REST API and Knockout.js. Reached 70% coverage w/ unit and integration tests.

### **Sustaining Engineering Manager**

Caradigm USA, LLC

2012 - 2013

Drove turn-around of Sustaining Engineering operations, team of 2 senior engineers and 6 offshore, consistently meeting all Service Level Agreements within 6 months; received *Employee Recognition Award*. Managed escalations from Professional Services and Customer Support organizations to engineering team.

## **Software Development Engineer II**

Microsoft Corporation

2010 - 2012

Spear-headed initial learning, adoption and training during transition of technology stacks from Linux, Java, Perl to Windows, C#/.NET, WCF, WPF, PowerShell.

### **Senior Software Engineer**

Sentillion, Inc.

1999 - 2010

Developed and Architected (portions of) Enterprise IAM solution with 99.999% uptime; a *KLAS Top 20* product. Direct customer support in startup environment.

### VOLUNTEER

## Software Development Elective, Instructor

The Master's School West Simsbury, CT 2014 - 2015

YMCA Swim Official

YMCA of Greater Hartford Granby, CT 2008 - 2014

#### **EDUCATION**

## **B.S. Management and Information Technology**

Daniel Webster College Nashua, NH